JAGADEESHWARA CHANDRA BOSE.K

Electrical and Electronics Engineering

|Jatayujagadeesh@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | || (+91)9705233003.||

Industry Preference: Automotive, Aerospace.

Tenali, Andhra Pradesh-522201.

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

A passionate **Electrical & Electronics Engineer** aiming for a challenging and responsible opportunity, to explore my skills and to gain experience from a professional organization and to continually develop my technical skills in the field of **Embedded IOT** domain.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

 Currently undergoing hands-on technical training program – Embedded IOT Systems Course at Emertxe Information Technologies, Bangalore.

 This course certified program, aligned with Skill India / NSDC under ESSC Duration - September 2022 – April 2023 expected.



AMARARAJA BATTERIES LIMITED, Chittoor - A.P.

IBD-Industrial Battery Division -- MVRLA-Medium Value Regulated Lead Acid Battery

Department : (ELECTRICAL TESTNG LAB – QUALITY ASSURANCE)

Role : Technician Trainee, Assistant Engineer.

Functional area : (BMS) - Battery management system.

Duration : Feb - 2019 to 23 - October - 2020.

Responsibilities:

• Electrical Testing Laboratory. (Discharge process – Compliance Test, Life Cycle Test)

• Manual Testing and Auto Testing and physical inspections.

• Tear down Analysis Laboratory and Field return Analysis.

• Analysis of failure in battery pack troubleshooting and preparing daily report.

• Data logger data reports as per R&D guidelines.

• Identifying root cause analysis using the data acquisition.

• Customer Inspections – Railway's, RITES, and Process Engineering, Internal Inspections.

INTERNSHIPS:

• Organization: ANDHRA PRADESH POWER GENERATION CORPORATION LIMITED

• Plant : Vijayawada Thermal Power Station. 5*210 KV & 500 Megawatts

• Designation: Industrial Internship Trainee

• Work place : 440KV Substation, Power Transformers, Battery chamber, Conveyers

• Grade : Good.

APGENCO

EDUCATION:

• Technical Training Program in Embedded IOT, Emertxe InformationTechnologies (Sept 2022–Till date)

• B.TECH in EEE, St. Mary's group of Institutions - 6.8% (2019 – 2022)

• Diploma in EEE, St. Mary's group of institutions - 71.20% (2015 – 2018)

• Class - X, SRS Municipal Boys high school - 8.2% (2014 – 2015)



B.Tech Final year Major Project:

Title : Modeling and simulation of the complete electric power train of a Hybrid electric vehicle.

Tools : MATLAB-simulation.

Project brief: The project aimed at designing a system that supplies constant DC power into 3-phase

AC power in different modes of operation and interfaces all the power sources to

Permanent Magnet Synchronous Motor.

Learnings: SVPWM controller, PI controller, VSI, Regenerative breaking, Design calculation.

Diploma Final year project:

Title : Voltage source based AC – DC converter.

Project brief: An AC-DC converter using a voltage source would involve using a circuit to convert an

alternating current (AC) input into a direct current (DC) output. This can be achieved

through the use of a rectifier, by only allowing current to flow in one direction.

Learnings: Rectifiers, circuit design, power conversion.

PROJECTS IN EMERTXE:

Module: C Program

Title : Image Steganography using LSB Encoding and Decoding.

Project brief: The objective was to send a secret text file encoded inside an image of bmp file format.

Encoded the length of the secret text and then encoded the data into the LSB of the image bytes. The decoding process involves decoding the length and then decoding the

text bit by bit. The final output is the secret text after decoding.

Tools: Ubuntu OS, Terminal, Command line arguments.

Learnings: Learned to transform the embedded information to the destination without changing

properties of the original image, Overcame difficulties while performing bitwise manipulation of data to embed as well to retrieve the data from the destination image which has embed as well to retrieve the data from destination image which has been solved after self-introspection.

Module: Arduino

Title : Industrial Machine State Monitoring System

Project brief: The purpose of this machine is to convert two ESP with each other as it senses DHT 11

Humidity vale from one ESP and send that data to another ESP through Wi-Fi.

The second ESP was connected to Thing speak through API key to get data and display data in graphical form. Second ESP was connected to mobile hot-spot to access data and send to Think speak. Hence, humidity value get continuously gathered and send to cloud

to show graphical data.

Tools : Arduino, ESP32 Node MCU

Learnings: This project helps to learn creating APN and client to communicate with each other to

send and share data to cloud.

Technical Skills:

Programming Languages : C programming, Shell scripting, Python, Arduino.

System programming : Linux Kernel system Ubuntu, Windows.
Simulation tools : MATLAB-simulation, LT spice, P sim.

RELEVANT SKILLS:

KEY SKILLS:

• Problem solving (4W 1H Technique)

• Kaizen implementation.

• 5s implementation.

PERSONAL INTERESTS:

• Investing time to learn money.

• Training body to fit and hygienic.

• Spending time with me.

POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY AND SOCIAL WORK

NATIONAL CADET CORPS [NCC], 22Andhra Bn, Tenali – Andhrapradesh.

2012-2014

- NCC-"A" with certificate rank holder
- All INDIA TREKKING EXPEDITION AP TREK 2013 Camp Tirupathi, Andharpradesh, India.
- Annual Training Camp Tenali, Andhrapradesh, India.
- School people leader for two years of SRS municipal high school.
- President of the School Student Body for two consecutive years of SMGIG.